kubernetes a tool for managing and automating containerized workloads in
kubernetes 一种用于在云中管理和自动化容器化工作负载的工具
the cloud imagine you have an orchestra think of
想象你有一个管弦乐队 把
each individual musician as a docker container
每个音乐家想象成一个 docker容器
to create beautiful music we need a conductor to manage the musicians and
来创作优美的音乐 我们需要一个指挥来管理音乐家并
set the tempo now imagine the conductor as kubernetes
设置节奏现在想象指挥是 kubernetes
and the orchestra as an app like robinhood when the markets are closed an
和当市场关闭时，管弦乐队
app like robinhood isn't doing much but when they open it
就像 robinhood 这样的应用程序 robinhood 这样的应用程序并没有做太多的事情，但是当它们打开时，它
needs to fulfill millions of trades for overpriced stocks like tesla and shopify
需要为特斯拉和 shopify 等高价股票完成数百万笔
kubernetes is the tool that orchestrates the infrastructure to handle the
交易 kubernetes 是协调基础设施以处理
changing workload it can scale containers across multiple
不断变化的工具 工作负载 它可以在多
machines and if one fails it knows how to replace it with a new one a system
台机器上扩展容器，如果其中一台出现故障，它知道如何用新的替换它
deployed on kubernetes is known as a cluster
部署在 kubernetes 上的系统被称为集群
the brain of the operation is known as the control plane it exposes an api
操作的大脑被称为控制平面 它公开了一个 API
server that can handle both internal and external requests to manage the cluster
服务器，可以 处理内部和外部请求以管理集群
it also contains its own key value database called
它还包含自己的键值数据库，称为
etcd used to store important information about running the cluster
etcd 用于存储有关运行集群的重要信息
what it's managing is one or more worker machines called nodes
它所管理的是一个或多个称为节点的工作机器，
when you hear node think of a machine each node is running something called a
当您听到 node 想到一台机器时，每个节点都在运行一个叫做
cubelet which is a tiny application that runs on
cubelet 的东西，它是一个运行在机器上的微型应用程序，
the machine to communicate back with the main control plane mother ship
用于进行通信
inside of each node we have multiple pods which is the smallest deployable
在每个节点内部都有主控制平面母舰，我们有多个pod，这是 Kubernetes 中最小的可部署
unit in kubernetes when you hear pod think of a pot of
单元，当您听到 pod 想到随着工作负载增加而
whales or containers running together as the workload increases kubernetes can
一起运行的一盆鲸鱼或容器时，kubernetes 可以
automatically scale horizontally by adding more nodes to the cluster
通过添加更多节点来自动水平扩展
in the process it takes care of complicated things like networking
在此过程中，它负责处理复杂的事情，例如网络
secret management persistent storage and so on
秘密管理持久存储等
it's designed for high availability and one way it achieves that is by
maintaining a replica set which is just a set of running pods or containers
ready to go at any given time as a developer you
作为开发人员，您可以在任何给定时间
define objects in yaml that describe the desired state of your cluster
在 yaml 中定义描述所需统计信息的对象 例如，您的集群中的 e
for example we might have an nginx deployment that has a replica set with
我们可能有一个 nginx部署，该部署在 spec 字段中有一个包含三个 pod 的副本集，
three pods in the spec field we can define exactly
我们可以准确定义
how it should behave like its containers volumes ports and so on you can then
它的行为方式，就像它的容器卷端口一样，然后您可以
take this configuration and use it to provision and scale containers
采用此配置并将其用于
automatically and ensure that they're always up and running and healthy
自动配置和扩展容器，并确保它们始终处于运行状态和健康状态，
this has been kubernetes in 100 seconds like and subscribe for more and you can
这已经是 100 秒内的 kubernetes喜欢并订阅更多内容，您可以
support my work by sponsoring me on github or by becoming a pro member at
通过在 github 上赞助我或成为
fireship io for even more content thanks for watching and i will see you
fireship io 的专业会员来支持我的工作 更多内容感谢观看，我们
in the next one
下期再见